[
    {
        "title": "What is Active Listening?",
        "info": [{
            "type": "video/youtube",
            "link": "https://www.youtube.com/embed/rzsVh8YwZEQ"
        },{
            "type": "text",
            "text": "Active listening requires us as listeners to capture what the sender is communicating from the sender's point of view through verbal and non-verbal cues.​ More than that, we must convey to the sender that we are seeing things from the sender's point of view.​ We can never be sure to understand another person completely or in detail. Therefore, it is essential in active listening that the listener frequently and continuously validates the accuracy of understanding in order to keep distortion and misunderstandings at a minimum."
        }],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is active listening all about what the other person is saying?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "No, it's about what they are saying and what their body language is showing."
            },
            {
                "question": "What is active listening?",
                "options": [
                    "The listener is genuinely interested in hearing and understanding the other person's point of view and therefore listens intently. Assuming to have heard correctly the listener does not say anything but indicates interest and attention by nonverbal aspects of communication like by maintaining eye contact and periodically nodding or smiling.",
                    "A listener reflects back to the sender his or her impression of what is expressed without judging.",
                    "Sound enters someone's ears but there is little chance or even attempt to comprehend or respond (e.g., listening to someone while reading the newspaper)."
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "help": [
                    "\"Active listening requires us as listeners to capture what the sender is communicating from the sender's point of view. More than that, we have to convey to the sender that we are seeing things from the sender's point of view. We can never be sure to understand another person completely or in detail.  Therefore it is essential in active listening that the listener frequently and continuously validates the accuracy of understanding in order to keep distortion and misunderstandings at a minimum.\" (Bauer and Figl, 2008)",
                    "\"Active listening requires us as listeners to capture what the sender is communicating from the sender's point of view. More than that, we have to convey to the sender that we are seeing things from the sender's point of view. We can never be sure to understand another person completely or in detail.  Therefore it is essential in active listening that the listener frequently and continuously validates the accuracy of understanding in order to keep distortion and misunderstandings at a minimum.\" (Bauer and Figl, 2008)"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "Does the listener only have to attentively listen and read the speaker's body language?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "No, it's important that the listener reinforces that they are listening, for example, through paraphrasing.​"
            },
            {
                "question": "Should the listener ask questions?",
                "answer": true,
                "help": "Asking can help the listener clarify something he might have misunderstood and it also shows the speaker that the listener is interested in and understanding what he is saying."
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Bauer, C., & Figl, K. (2008, October). \"Active listening\" in written online communication-a case study in a course on \"soft skills for computer scientists\". In 2008 38th Annual Frontiers in Education Conference (pp. F2C-1). IEEE.",
                "url": "https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?tp=&arnumber=4720282"
            },
            {
                "text": "GCFLearnFree.org. (2019, Jan 29), Active Listening [Video]. Youtube.",
                "url": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rzsVh8YwZEQ"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title": "What are the benefits of Active Listening?",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Active listening has a lot of benefits. These are:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "Better understanding - The fact that the listener also talks for clarification or paraphrasing, means that both the speaker and the listener can be sure that all was understood.",
                    "Increased availability - As someone is listened to, their availability to hear the other person will increase.",
                    "Showing respect - Actively listening to someone will show our respect for them and what they have to say.",
                    "Greater empathy - Through active listening it is possible to better understand a person's emotional state, which will allow the listener to interact with the speaker in a more empathetic manner.",
                    "Greater quality of information - By intervening, the listener can guide the speaker to reach the core of his or hers problem/reason for talking."
                ]
            }
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Are faster conversations a benefit of Active Listening?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "No, actively listening does not make conversations faster."
            },
            {
                "question": "What is a benefit of Active Listening?",
                "options": [
                    "Better memory of conversations.",
                    "Better at speaking.",
                    "Better understanding.",
                    "All of the above."
                ],
                "answer": 2
            },
            {
                "question": "What is not a benefit of Active Listening?",
                "options": [
                    "Greater respect between the speaker and the listener.",
                    "Lesser quality of information.",
                    "Greater empathy.",
                    "Increased availability."
                ],
                "answer": 1
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Bauer, C., & Figl, K. (2008, October). \"Active listening\" in written online communication-a case study in a course on \"soft skills for computer scientists\". In 2008 38th Annual Frontiers in Education Conference (pp. F2C-1). IEEE.",
                "url": "https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?tp=&arnumber=4720282"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title":"Some non-verbal strategies for active listening and what they are.",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Some examples of non-verbal strategies are:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "\"Keep an Open Mind: Thinking about listening might make you feel tense in the moment. The effective listener is instead calm with a focused and alert mind.\"",
                    "\"Identify Distractions: In any setting where you are expected to listen, you encounter numerous distractions. For instance, the father sitting in the living room watching television, might want to turn off the television to better enable him to listen to his son when he comes into the room saying\"",
                    "\"Come Prepared: Another useful strategy is to come prepared when you can. Any time you enter a listening situation with some advance working knowledge of the speaker and what might be expected of you as a listener, you will be better able to adjust and engage more deeply in what is being said.\"",
                    "\"Take Notes: (...) The manner in which you take the notes is up to you; what is important is the fact that you are listening and working to process what is being said.\""
                ]
            }
            
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is taking notes a stratagy that promotes active listening ?",
                "answer": true,
                "help": "Yes, taking notes promotes active listening."
            },
            {
                "question": "Which is a non-verbal stratagy for active listening?",
                "options": [
                    "Summarizing",
                    "Identify Distractions",
                    "Create Distrations",
                    "Increase availability."
                ],
                "answer": 2
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Jenn Q. Goddu \"Strategies to Enhance Listening.\" (2021, January 4). Queens University of Charlotte.",
                "url": "https://socialsci.libretexts.org/Bookshelves/Communication/Public_Speaking/Public_Speaking_(The_Public_Speaking_Project)/04%3A_Listening_Effectively/4.06%3A_Strategies_to_Enhance_Listening"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title":"Some verbal barriers to active listening",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Some examples of verbal antidotes are:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "\"Judging\"",
                    "\"Interrupting with another subject\"",
                    "\"Giving advice/Solutions*\"",
                    "\"Sharing your experience*\""
                ]
            }
            
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is sharing your experience a verbal barrier to active listening?",
                "answer": true,
                "help": "Yes, sharing your experience is a non-verbal barrier."
            },
            {
                "question": "Which is a verbal barrier to active listening?",
                "options": [
                    "Summarizing",
                    "Looking through (only) your lens",
                    "Keeping a Open Mind",
                    "Giving advice"
                ],
                "answer": 4
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Sá, S. , Gonçalves, A. ,Babynyuk, R. (2021). Active Listening [52]. Communication Skills in Computer \n Science and Engineering I, Instituto Superior Técnico. https://fenix.tecnico.ulisboa.pt/downloadFile/845043405555880/Active%20listening.pdf",
                "url": ""
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title":"Some non-verbal barriers to active listening",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Some examples of non-verbal antidotes are:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "\"Distraction\"",
                    "Lack of eye contact",
                    "Bad posture",
                    "Lack of preparation"
                ]
            }
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is Lack of preparation a non-verbal barrier to active listening?",
                "answer": true,
                "help": "Yes, Lack of preparation is a non-verbal barrier."
            },
            {
                "question": "which is a non-verbal barrier to active listening?",
                "options": [
                    "Verbalizing Emotions",
                    "Judging",
                    "Bad posture",
                    "Giving advice"
                ],
                "answer": 3
            }

        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Semigran,R. (2019, August 1). \"6 TIPS FOR BETTER ACTIVE LISTENING\" . Goodwin College of Professional Studies",
                "url": "https://drexel.edu/goodwin/professional-studies-blog/overview/2019/August/tips-for-better-active-listening/"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title": "What are some verbal strategies for Active Listening?",
        "info": [{
                "type": "text",
                "text": "There are some verbal strategies that can help us actively listen, such as:"
            },{
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "Paraphrasing - It shows interest and encourage others to keep talking. It consists in restating the information spoken with the listener's own words.",
                    "Verbalizing Emotions - It shows the speaker that the listener understands his or her feelings and helps build empathy.",
                    "Asking - Asking is done with the intention of acquiring more information, which will make the speaker think the listener is invested in the conversation.",
                    "Summarizing - It shows the speaker that the listener has understood what was said previously and what the context for further conversation is.",
                    "Clarifying - Although similar to asking, clarifying has to do with asking about something that was said already."
                ]
            }
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is repeating every single word the speaker says a good verbal strategy for Active Listening?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "It is important to be able to repeat the message, but through the listener's own words. This is called paraphrasing."
            },
            {
                "question": "\"I showed up at 8:55am for the 9am and they still said I was late!\" Which of these options is paraphrasing?",
                "options": [
                    "That must have made you really angry.",
                    "So they said you were late even though you arrived 5 minutes early...",
                    "They said you were late?"
                ],
                "answer": 1
            },
            {
                "question": "\"I showed up at 8:55am for the 9am and they still said I was late!\" Which of these options is clarifying?",
                "options": [
                    "That must have made you really angry.",
                    "So they said you were late even though you arrived 5 minutes early...",
                    "They said you were late?"
                ],
                "answer": 2
            },
            {
                "question": "\"I showed up at 8:55am for the 9am and they still said I was late!\" Which of these options is verbalizing emotions?",
                "options": [
                    "That must have made you really angry.",
                    "So they said you were late even though you arrived 5 minutes early...",
                    "They said you were late?"
                ],
                "answer": 0
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Bauer, C., & Figl, K. (2008, October). \"Active listening\" in written online communication-a case study in a course on \"soft skills for computer scientists\". In 2008 38th Annual Frontiers in Education Conference (pp. F2C-1). IEEE.",
                "url": "https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?tp=&arnumber=4720282"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title":"Paraphrase/Reformulation in conversations",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "video/youtube",
                "link": "https://www.youtube.com/embed/BjUCF_Z146c"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"Paraphrasing is when a person reads or actively listens to a message and is able to clearly express it back in their own words (written or spoken). In a paraphrase, the original ideas or meaning are maintained, but the wording has to be your own. Like active listening, paraphrasing is a skill that needs to be taught explicitly, practiced, and developed.\" (\"Listening: The Key to 2 Way Communication\", n.d.)"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Some important points (but not all) that we should take into consideration when paraphrasing are, as described by McNamara (2012):"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "\"Put the focus of the paraphrase on what the other person implied, not on what you wanted him/her to imply, e.g., don’t say, “I believe what you meant to say was …”.  Instead, say “If I’m hearing you right, you conveyed that …?”\"",
                    "\"Phrase the paraphrase as a question, “So you’re saying that …?”, so that the other person has the responsibility and opportunity to refine his/her original comments in response to your question.\"",
                    "\"Put the ownership of the paraphrase on yourself, e.g., “If I’m hearing you right …?” or “If I understand you correctly …?”\"",
                    "\"Put the ownership of the other person’s words on him/her, e.g., say “If I understand you right, you’re saying that …?” or “… you believe that  …?” or “… you feel that …?”\""
                ]
            }
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which of these is a paraphrase for this statement: \"I'm having a hard time communicating with Bill and I don't know what's going on.\"? (\"How to Paraphrase\", n.d.)",
                "options": [
                    "Why do you think that is happening?",
                    "I'm getting a sense that you might be frustrated because of this situation.",
                    "So, what you are saying is that you and Bill aren't getting along so well, and that is making it hard to keep up with what's going on. Is that right?"
                ],
                "answer": 2,
                "help": [
                    "In this case, the listener is asking a question to allow the speaker to develop their idea further, but this isn't a paraphrase.",
                    "This is another active listening technique, Verbalizing emotions."
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "For the statement \"I'm not feeling well today.\" (\"How to Paraphrase\", n.d.), is \"From what I'm understanding, you got sick, right?\" a valid paraphrase?",
                "answer": true,
                "help": "This is actually a paraphrase for this statement. It could even help to clarify a misunderstanding, as someone not feeling well might not be necessarily the same as being ill."
            },
            {
                "question": "Consider the statement: \"I'm still on my way to work, I might arrive a bit late today.\". Regarding the statement, is \"What happened for that to be the case?\" a paraphrase for it?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "This question is not a paraphrase for this question, it doesn't reformulate what was said, it is a clarifying question, as it allows the speaker to expand their point, for the listener to get a better understanding of what was said. This is the topic that should be discussed after this module."
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Conversation Sparks. (2017, September 12). How to Be a Better Listener: Paraphrasing [Video]. Youtube.",
                "url": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BjUCF_Z146c"
            },
            {
                "text": "Listening: The Key to 2 Way Communication. (n.d.). Retrieved from ",
                "url": "https://selspace.ca/modules/effective-communication/effective-communication-intermediate/active-listening-and-paraphrasing/"
            },
            {
                "text": "McNamara, C. (2012, January 26). Useful Communications Skills — How to Paraphrase and Summarize. Blog: Coaching and Action Learning.",
                "url": "https://managementhelp.org/blogs/personal-and-professional-coaching/2012/01/26/useful-communications-skills-how-to-paraphrase-and-summarize/"
            },
            {
                "text": "How to Paraphrase. (n.d.). Retrieved from",
                "url": "http://www.maximumadvantage.com/how-to-paraphrase.html"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title": "Clarification questions",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"Clarifying questions are questions that the listener asks the speaker in an attempt to eliminate or prevent any misunderstanding, confusion or ambiguity. By asking this type of question after receiving the message, the listener makes sure they properly understood the message and obtain important additional information. The speaker also benefits by being reassured that their audience is actively listening and genuinely interested in what they have to say.\""
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"There are two main types of clarifying questions:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "Open clarifying questions: They ask the speaker to elaborate on a certain part of their message. Most of them have the form of when, why, where or how types of questions and encourage the speaker to openly expand their thoughts and ideas.",
                    "Closed clarifying questions: They simply reiterate a part of the message and ask the speaker to confirm or deny that what the listener understood was indeed what the speaker was trying to express to their audience.\""
                ]
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Some examples of clarifying questions could be:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"Open questions regarding the speaker's views and opinions"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "*Speaker: “I think the company should invest in new technology early next year.”*"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Clarifying questions:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "What do you consider to be new technology?",
                    "Why do you think it should be early next year?",
                    "Where can that take us?",
                    "How did you determine that?\""
                ]
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"Closed questions for clarifying instructions"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "*Speaker: “You need to make sure that we are getting the best possible price when we purchase new technology.”*"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Clarifying questions:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "So I need to check the market and find out if anyone else is selling at a lower price?",
                    "By purchasing new technology do you mean buying the pieces of equipment that we already talked about?",
                    "So I need to be absolutely certain of that before I report back to you?\""
                ]
            }
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "(Dawson, 2019) Consider the statement: \"Employees will be entitled to 10 paid personal days each year.\" Which of these is a clarifying question, regarding this statement?",
                "options": [
                    "\"What is a personal day?\"",
                    "\"Don’t you think ten days is a bit too generous?\"",
                    "\"Don’t we need to do more research on best practices before going further?\"",
                    "\"Why is this item on the agenda today?\""
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "help": [
                    "This question is actually expressing an opinion, it won't help clarifying anything about what was stated.",
                    "This question is expressing an opinion, that some more research should be done before discussing the topic. But it doesn't clarify anything.",
                    "This question might even be a clarifying question, but it is unrelated to the policy that was presented."
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "(Indeed Editorial Team, 2021) Consider the statement: \"You need to make sure that we are getting the best possible price when we purchase new technology.\" And now consider the question:\" What do you consider to be new technology?\" Is this a clarifying question for the statement above?",
                "answer": true,
                "help": "This question is a clarification question, as the listener is asking the speaker to further explain their point of view, to make sure they are both on the same page about what the new technology is."
            },
            {
                "question": "(Dawson, 2019) Consider the following clarifying question: \"Are you sure we can fulfill our long-term ambitions this way?\" What type of question is this?",
                "options": [
                    "Open question",
                    "Closed question"
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "help": [
                    "An open question would encourage the speaker to further elaborate on their view point, which is not the case here."
                ]
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Indeed Editorial Team. (2021, March 18). What Are Clarifying Questions and When Should You Ask Them? indeed.",
                "url": "https://www.indeed.com/career-advice/career-development/clarifying-questions"
            },
            {
                "text": "Dawson, T. (2019, June 13). Clarifying questions — what they are & why you should know how to ask them. Theo Dawson.",
                "url": "https://theo-dawson.medium.com/clarifying-questions-what-they-are-why-you-should-know-how-to-ask-them-27cadd8054fe"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title": "Identify and use the verbalisation of emotions?",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Verbalization of emotions is to verbalize the emotions conveyd by the person talking in order to show that we understand what the person is/was feeling at the time."
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Some examples of verbalization of emotions could be:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Alice:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "After I got home the dog had chewed the top part of my laptop! I couldn't believe what I was seeing..."
                ]
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Bob:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "That's awful, you must've felt really mad."
                ]
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Alice:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "Yes, but most of all I felt really sad."
                ]
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "As we can see Bob starts by verbalizing the possible emotion (feeling mad) that Alice was feeling. Then afterwards Alice verbalizes her emotions by stating that she was sad with the situation."
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text":  "FUN FACT: \"Putting words to feelings may be one of the most important aspects of the affects-language-cognition interaction. It turns out that children can link words and feelings much earlier than thought—with tremendous benefits.\" (Holinger P., 2018)"
            }

        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is the act of conveying your feelings through gestures or non-verbal communication considered verbalization of emotions?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "Verbalization of emotions as the name states includes verbalization, so the act of verbalizing words is needed"
            },
            {
                "question": "For the statement \"After this long day I was really glad that I could grab something to eat, I was starving\" what is considered verbalization of emotions?",
                "options": [
                    "I was starving",
                    "I was really glad",
                    "Both"
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "help": "\"While emotions are associated with bodily reactions that are activated through neurotransmitters and hormones released by the brain, feelings are the conscious experience of emotional reactions.\" (Farnsworth B., 2020)"
            },{
                "question": "Consider the statement: \"I'm so disappointed with the way I presented my report today\" is there a verbalization of emotions in this case?",
                "answer": true,
                "help": "This is actually a verbalization of emotions since the person stating this is saying that they are disappointed."
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Holinger, P., (2018, June).  Putting Words to Feelings Verbalization of affects has a major effect on development. . Psychology Today Blog",
                "url": "https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/great-kids-great-parents/201806/putting-words-feelings"
            },
            {
                "text": "Farnsworth, B., (2020, April). How to Measure Emotions and Feelings (And the Difference Between Them). Imotions Blog ",
                "url": "https://imotions.com/blog/difference-feelings-emotions/"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title": "Identify and use summarization",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"A summary is a synthesis of the key ideas of a piece of writing, restated in your own words – i.e., paraphrased.  You may write a summary as a stand-alone assignment or as part of a longer paper.  Whenever you summarize, you must be careful not to copy the exact wording of the original source.\" (Academic Integrity at MIT, 2021)"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "With this definition of summary we can now give our own definition of what is summarization in the context of active listening."
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Summarization much like paraphrasing is to verbalize what as just been said by another person in a condensed way (i.e. stating the key topics) in order to convey the understanding of what is being said. In the case of summarization it is more than just one concept/phrase. It also should end with a question, in order to ask the other person if what you just said was right. "
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "A good example of summarization could be:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Alice:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "After  7 months trying to solve the issue in the cluster that was affecting the account backups of the clients we were able to give the system an overall and fix it. This was done by providing a new software patch for Apache because one of the features was deprecated and then rebooting all the assets."
                ]
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Bob:"
            },
            {
                "type": "text/list",
                "items": [
                    "You're teeling me that the issue with the clients backs that we were trying to solve for months, was solved by upgrading the Apache software and then rebooting the system, right?"
                ]
            }
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is it summarization if a person ends their summary and doesn't ask the other a question like \"right?\" at the end in order to check if what he/she just stated was right?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "Summarization should end with a question, in order to ask the other person if what you just said was right."
            },
            {
                "question": "For the following statements:\"We went to the restaurant there was one menu for fish, one for meat and one for vegetarian. After being there for an astonishing hour we started to notice that cockroaches, crickets, praying mantis and other insects comming out of the kitchen. It was truly terrifying.\".What could be a good summarization of this text?",
                "options": [
                    "So your went to the restaurant that had a menu for each type of dish and after being there for quite some time you started to see insects comming out of the kitchen.",
                    "So your went to the restaurant that had a menu for each type of dish and after being there for quite some time you started to see insects comming out of the kitchen,right?",
                    "So your went to the restaurant that had a menu for each type of dish and after being there for quite some time you started to see insects comming out of the kitchen, it must've been terrifying."
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "help": "Summarization should end with a question, in order to ask the other person if what you just said was right."
            },
            {
                "question": "What is a benefit of good summarization?",
                "options": [
                    "People hearing you more than if you didn't use summarization",
                    "Showing that you can understand what the other person is saying",
                    "Having a better idea of what the other person is truly saying and conveying this to them in order to iron out misunderstandings between what is being said and what is being listened"
                ],
                "answer": 2
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Academic Integrity at MIT, (2021, November 3). Academic writing by Academic Integrity at MIT at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT). Retrived November 3, 2021, from ",
                "url": "https://integrity.mit.edu/handbook/academic-writing/summarizing"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "title":"(Understand the advantages of Active Listening in the IT world)",
        "info": [
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "Currently IT is a software based industry and there is an assumption that communication is not a relevant and that our work quality mostly comes from out technical skills alone. But this is not true since software and IT is an iterative and dynamic industry. This being the case, communication and thus active listening are factors that should be deemed as important, if not more, as our technical skills."
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"Being an active listener can also help you learn and improve. By focusing on what the others are saying instead of your own opinion, you’ll be able to catch flaws in your own thinking. Your ideas will change, evolve, and hopefully get better overtime. The others will complete them with new and fresh insights.\" (Active Listening for Developers, 2021)"
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "In our work space, active listening can be our most powerful tool when it comes to efficiency, effective learning and good team building. By having a good and effective communication process within our team, it allows for a better knowledge sharing between the members."
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "\"One of the biggest problems in communication, according to this other study, is misunderstanding; we use the same words, but the meaning we attach to them can be different. This meaning depends on our internal world: our experience, our values, what we think is right or wrong. In that regard, the more you’ll “know” the persons around you, the more you’ll be able to decipher what they really mean.\""
            },
            {
                "type": "text",
                "text": "When meeting with clients or learning from our superiors, there are some cases where misunderstanding can be a barrier for the product development, as a small misunderstanding can mean a big difference between what was invisioned and what was developed. So, the use of the active listening techniques discussed and practiced throughout the previous modules can be a huge differentiator when it comes to truly undestanding what is expected from us as professionals."
            }
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Is engaging product presentation a benefit of the good use of active listening techniques in an IT workplace?",
                "answer": false,
                "help": "This is indeed a benefit for our product, but it doesn't come from the use of active listening techniques. Rather, it comes from the use of other kinds of techniques, such as those from public speaking."
            },
            {
                "question": "Using what you learned in the modules on this website, select which of these can be an advantage of using clarification questions in the workplace (Select the most fitting answer).",
                "options": [
                    "Better relationship within the team.",
                    "Procrastination.",
                    "Less misunderstandings.",
                    "Faster work."
                ],
                "answer": 2,
                "help": ["Although this is a true benefit that can come from the use of active listening skills, it might not come directly from the use of clarification questions, but from other techniques, such as verbalization of emotions, for instance.",
                "This is not an advantage for our workplace, much on the contrary, it should be avoided.",
                "Even if this can be an advantage generated by the use of clarification questions, this might, most of the times, not be true. There are other advantages that can be more directly associated with this technique."
                ]
            }
        ],
        "ref": [
            {
                "text": "Active Listening for Developers. (2021, April 27). The Valuable Dev. Retrieved from ",
                "url": "https://thevaluable.dev/active-listening-communication-developer/"
            }
        ]
    }
]
